Office of the Chancellor fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Office of the Chancellor fonds
1961-2011, predominant 1961-1985
F-3
1.5 m of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Office of the Chancellor
The Office of Chancellor of S.F.U. was formally established with the appointment of the first officer of the University and first Chancellor, Dr. Gordon M. Shrum, on 9 May 1963. The functions of the Chancellor were laid out in the Universities Act (SBC 1963 c. 52, ss. 11-14; RSBC 1979, c. 419, ss. 11-17), which stated that the chief role of the Chancellor was to confer degrees. The Chancellor was elected by the members of Convocation, and presided as chair of this body. The Chancellor also sat as a member of other bodies, including the Board of Governors and the Senate. The incumbent to this position also represented the University at various events and took on speaking engagements in keeping with the largely ceremonial nature of the office.
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on the name of the body.
The fonds of the Office of Chancellor consists of records created and received in the course of carrying out the functions of the Chancellor. The activities documented include correspondence on various subjects; participation in university committees and other bodies including the Board of Governors and Senate; and liaison with external bodies, including professional associations and other universities. The types of documents include meeting agenda and minutes, brochures, correspondence, memoranda, publications, reports, and transcripts.
The material mainly covers the tenure of the first four Chancellors of SFU, up to 1985. There is a single post-1985 item, a photograph book in series 5 relating to Brandt C. Louie, Chancellor from 2006-2011.
Coté, Paul T.; Diamond, Jack; Caple, Kenneth P.; Shrum, Gordon
The records were transferred directly from the Office of the Chancellor.
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. Further accruals are expected.
Consult the inventories to the Board of Governors, Senate, and Office of the President fonds.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as required by law. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
File lists are available.
- Dr. Gordon Merritt Shrum papers, 1961 - 1985; F-3-1; 1.39 m of textual records
  published
  Sub-series consists of records made and received by Dr. Shrum in the course of his activities as Chancellor. Subjects and activities documented include planning and construction of the university, selection of architects (including the lead design firm Erickson Massey Architects), meetings of the Buildings and Site Committee, correspondence with various architects, speaking engagements, fundraising, and correspondence with external agencies. Record types include correspondence, meeting agenda and minutes, memoranda, reports, and transcripts of two interviews (with Clive Cocking and Peter Stursberg). Correspondents whose names appear in file titles are registered as Access Points.
  National Research Council; Cocking, Clive; Stursberg, Peter; Erickson, Arthur; Buildings and Site Committee; Massey, Geoffrey; University of British Columbia (UBC)
  Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as required by law. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1961 - 1963; F-3-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 3-1)
    Textual records
    Pending review
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1963; F-3-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 3-1)
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1964; F-3-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 3-1)
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1964 - 1965; F-3-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 3-1)
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1965; F-3-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 3-1)
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1965; F-3-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 3-1)
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1966; F-3-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 3-1)
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1966; F-3-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 3-1)
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1967; F-3-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 3-1)
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1967; F-3-1-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 3-1)
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1968; F-3-1-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 3-2)
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1968; F-3-1-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 3-2)
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1969; F-3-1-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 3-2)
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1969; F-3-1-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 3-2)
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1970; F-3-1-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 3-2)
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1971; F-3-1-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 3-2)
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1972; F-3-1-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 3-2)
  - General correspondence: speaking engagements, 1972; F-3-1-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 3-2)
  - Congratulations on Chancellor's appointment, 1963; F-3-1-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 3-3)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1963; F-3-1-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 3-3)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1963; F-3-1-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 3-3)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1964; F-3-1-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 3-3)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1964; F-3-1-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 3-3)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1964; F-3-1-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 3-3)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1964; F-3-1-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 3-3)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1964; F-3-1-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 3-3)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1964; F-3-1-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 3-3)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1964; F-3-1-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 3-3)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1964; F-3-1-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 3-3)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1965; F-3-1-0-0-30 (Archival box - standard 3-3)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1965; F-3-1-0-0-31 (Archival box - standard 3-3)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1965; F-3-1-0-0-32 (Archival box - standard 3-3)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1965; F-3-1-0-0-33 (Archival box - standard 3-4)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1965; F-3-1-0-0-34 (Archival box - standard 3-4)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1965; F-3-1-0-0-35 (Archival box - standard 3-4)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1965; F-3-1-0-0-36 (Archival box - standard 3-4)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1965; F-3-1-0-0-37 (Archival box - standard 3-4)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1966; F-3-1-0-0-38 (Archival box - standard 3-4)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1966; F-3-1-0-0-39 (Archival box - standard 3-4)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1966; F-3-1-0-0-40 (Archival box - standard 3-4)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1966; F-3-1-0-0-41 (Archival box - standard 3-4)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1966; F-3-1-0-0-42 (Archival box - standard 3-4)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1966; F-3-1-0-0-43 (Archival box - standard 3-4)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1966; F-3-1-0-0-44 (Archival box - standard 3-5)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1966 - 1967; F-3-1-0-0-45 (Archival box - standard 3-5)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1967; F-3-1-0-0-46 (Archival box - standard 3-5)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1967; F-3-1-0-0-47 (Archival box - standard 3-5)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1967; F-3-1-0-0-48 (Archival box - standard 3-5)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1967; F-3-1-0-0-49 (Archival box - standard 3-5)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1967; F-3-1-0-0-50 (Archival box - standard 3-5)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1967; F-3-1-0-0-51 (Archival box - standard 3-5)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1967; F-3-1-0-0-52 (Archival box - standard 3-5)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1967; F-3-1-0-0-53 (Archival box - standard 3-5)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1967 - 1968; F-3-1-0-0-54 (Archival box - standard 3-6)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1968; F-3-1-0-0-55 (Archival box - standard 3-6)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1968; F-3-1-0-0-56 (Archival box - standard 3-6)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1968; F-3-1-0-0-57 (Archival box - standard 3-6)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1968; F-3-1-0-0-58 (Archival box - standard 3-6)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1968; F-3-1-0-0-59 (Archival box - standard 3-6)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1968; F-3-1-0-0-60 (Archival box - standard 3-6)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1968; F-3-1-0-0-61 (Archival box - standard 3-6)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1968; F-3-1-0-0-62 (Archival box - standard 3-6)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1968; F-3-1-0-0-63 (Archival box - standard 3-7)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1968; F-3-1-0-0-64 (Archival box - standard 3-7)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1968 - 1969; F-3-1-0-0-65 (Archival box - standard 3-7)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1969; F-3-1-0-0-66 (Archival box - standard 3-7)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1969; F-3-1-0-0-67 (Archival box - standard 3-7)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1969; F-3-1-0-0-68 (Archival box - standard 3-7)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1969; F-3-1-0-0-69 (Archival box - standard 3-7)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1970; F-3-1-0-0-70 (Archival box - standard 3-7)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1971; F-3-1-0-0-71 (Archival box - standard 3-7)
  - Chancellor's correspondence, 1972; F-3-1-0-0-72 (Archival box - standard 3-7)
  - SFU construction correspondence, 1963; F-3-1-0-0-73 (Archival box - standard 3-8)
    Open
  - SFU construction correspondence, 1964; F-3-1-0-0-74 (Archival box - standard 3-8)
    Restricted in whole
  - SFU construction correspondence, 1965; F-3-1-0-0-75 (Archival box - standard 3-8)
  - SFU construction correspondence, 1966; F-3-1-0-0-76 (Archival box - standard 3-8)
  - SFU construction correspondence, 1967; F-3-1-0-0-77 (Archival box - standard 3-8)
  - SFU construction correspondence, 1968; F-3-1-0-0-78 (Archival box - standard 3-8)
  - SFU construction, 1963 - 1964; F-3-1-0-0-79 (Archival box - standard 3-8)
  - SFU construction, 1964; F-3-1-0-0-80 (Archival box - standard 3-8)
  - Financial campaign, 1965; F-3-1-0-0-81 (Archival box - standard 3-8)
  - Financial campaign, 1965; F-3-1-0-0-82 (Archival box - standard 3-8)
  - Financial campaign, 1966 - 1968; F-3-1-0-0-83 (Archival box - standard 3-8)
  - Minutes of meetings with designing architects, 1963; F-3-1-0-0-84 (Archival box - standard 3-8)
  - Presidential Search correspondence, 1963; F-3-1-0-0-85 (Archival box - standard 3-8)
  - Site study, SFU, 1963; F-3-1-0-0-86 (Archival box - standard 3-9)
  - SFU, architectural competition invitation, F-3-1-0-0-87 (Archival box - standard 3-9)
  - SFU, newspaper proposal, 1964; F-3-1-0-0-88 (Archival box - standard 3-9)
  - SFU, permanent bursary endowment plan, 1968; F-3-1-0-0-89 (Archival box - standard 3-9)
  - Defence Orientation Conference Association, 1961 - 1971; F-3-1-0-0-90 (Archival box - standard 3-9)
  - EDP Data Centre (Director), 1969 - 1971; F-3-1-0-0-91 (Archival box - standard 3-9)
  - Honorary Professor of Physics (UBC), 1961; F-3-1-0-0-92 (Archival box - standard 3-9)
  - Joint Engineering Management Conference (Advisory Council), 1966 - 1972; F-3-1-0-0-93 (Archival box - standard 3-9)
  - National Research Council, Canada, 1962 - 1969; F-3-1-0-0-94 (Archival box - standard 3-9)
  - Organizations and memberships, 1961 - 1972; F-3-1-0-0-95 (Archival box - standard 3-9)
  - Park and Tilford Trophy, Trustee, 1968 - 1970; F-3-1-0-0-96 (Archival box - standard 3-9)
  - Travel, 1961 - 1964; F-3-1-0-0-97 (Archival box - standard 3-10)
  - Travel, 1965 - 1972; F-3-1-0-0-98 (Archival box - standard 3-10)
  - University of British Columbia, 1969 - 1972; F-3-1-0-0-99 (Archival box - standard 3-10)
    University of British Columbia (UBC); Textual records
  - Vancouver Club, 1964; F-3-1-0-0-100 (Archival box - standard 3-10)
    Vancouver Club; Textual records
  - Gala Dinner to Honour Gordon Merritt Shrum, 1983; F-3-1-0-0-101 (Archival box - standard 3-10)
  - Memorial service, 1985; F-3-1-0-0-102 (Archival box - standard 3-10)
  - Interview questions (Clive Cocking), 1985; F-3-1-0-0-103 (Archival box - standard 3-10)
  - Interview transcript (Clive Cocking), 1985; F-3-1-0-0-104 (Archival box - standard 3-10)
  - Interview transcript (Peter Stursburg), vol. 1, 1983; F-3-1-0-0-105 (Archival box - standard 3-10)
  - Interview transcript (Peter Stursburg), vol. 2, 1983; F-3-1-0-0-106 (Archival box - standard 3-10)
  - Tribute, 1985; F-3-1-0-0-107 (Archival box - standard 3-10)
  - Minute book - meetings with designing architects, 1963; F-3-1-0-0-108 (Archival box - small 3-12)
- Dr. Kenneth P. Caple papers, 1970 - 1975; F-3-2; 6 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records made and received by Dr. Kenneth P. Caple in the course of carrying out the duties of Chancellor. It includes correspondence and rolls of congratula.
  - Rolls of congratula, 1970; F-3-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 3-11)
  - Congratulatory messages, 1970; F-3-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 3-11)
  - Correspondence, 1970 - 1974; F-3-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 3-11)
  - Correspondence, 1970 - 1975; F-3-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 3-11)
- Jack Diamond papers, 1975 - 1978; F-3-3; 2 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records made and received by Jack Diamond in the course of carrying out the duties of Chancellor. It includes correspondence and memoranda.
  - Correspondence, 1975 - 1978; F-3-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 3-11)
- Dr. Paul T. Cote papers, 1978 - 1984; F-3-4; 5 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records made and received by Dr. Paul T. Coté in the course of carrying out the duties of Chancellor. It includes correspondence and memoranda.
  - Correspondence, 1978 - 1981; F-3-4-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 3-11)
  - Correspondence, 1979 - 1981; F-3-4-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 3-11)
  - Correspondence, 1982 - 1984; F-3-4-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 3-11)
- Publications, 2011; F-3-5; 2 cm of textual records
  Series consists of publications issued by or relating to the Office of the Chancellor.
  - Memories of a Chancellor: Brandt C. Louie, Chancellor 2016-2011, F-3-5-0-0-1; 1 book (Shelf Map cabinet)
    File consists of a book released around 2011 of photographs taken by SFU photographers relating to the tenure of Brandt C. Louie from 2006-2011. The book appears to have been prepared by SFU's Creative Services Group around 2011 on the occasion of Louie's completion of his term of office.
    Louie, Brandt C.; Learning and Instructional Development Centre; Textual records